Trevor N Suarez

he/him/his

Software Engineer (with a Backend Focus)

INTRO

Software Engineer with an obsession for detail. Open source advocate. Lover of tools. Constantly echoing the "Principle of least astonishment".

I want to design and develop unique, socially responsible, software (applications and tools) that positively affect the world. My passion lies in creating intuitive user experiences.

Quality over haste. Sustainability and maintainability. Don't recreate the wheel, but construct new wheels with stronger and lighter materials.

EXPERIENCE

Slack Technologies, LLC - Senior Software Engineer, Backend

MAY 2020 - MAR 2023

I was hired specifically to work on the "Workflows" product within Slack, a no-code app builder that enables non-technical users to empower integrations and custom logical workflows in Slack.

Originally a separate microservice written in Go and integrated through a proxy to Slack's main Hack-based monolith, I was responsible for the creation of new features and optimizations for critical scale as the application received over 1 million workflow executions (and FAR more API requests) a day.

I was tasked as part of a large team to develop the new Slack "Platform", which included migrating the original Workflow service logic into the main Slack monolith, re-engineering original features with new considerations for scale and future capability.

I worked with a team to develop a configurable visibility mechanism for event triggers, which became a US patent: <u>US 11,611,519 B1</u>.

My time at Slack exposed me to the challenges and rewards of scale, both in terms of user-activity and team size.

RemoteHQ — Software Engineer

DEC 2018 - JAN 2020

Worked as part of a TINY (4 engineers max) team over the course of 13 months. Expanded the backend API framework while developing core features end-to-end.

Most time was spent writing Go, developing HTTP REST APIs, and creating new features, while efforting towards a self-documented, self-describing, wholly consistent resource interface.

Worked on a Vue.js/TypeScript front-end part-time there also.

All applications and services were containerized in Docker, using Docker Compose locally and AWS ECS in production.

Robin Powered, Inc. — Engineer

MAR 2014 - DEC 2018

I spent most of my time engineering the platform backend.

Was the main contributor to the public/private Robin API, which was written on top of a framework that I initially created and then continued to develop with my team.

I also developed microservices in Go, including a SQS-based job queue executor.

Helped directly manage the platform's infrastructure in AWS, provisioning server images using Packer, Puppet, etc.

I also wrote the beta Android app.

PRIMARY SKILLS

Go (Golang), PHP, Hack (Hacklang), TypeScript, JavaScript

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Vitess, Redis

REST, gRPC, AWS (EC2, RDS, SQS)

Linux, Docker, Bash, Git

SECONDARY SKILLS

Java, Python, Dart

MongoDB, Kubernetes

Svelte, Vue.js, Android SDK

AWARDS

US 11,611,519 B1 – *US Patent*

ISSUED SEP 2021

Event Trigger Visibility Within A Group-Based Communication System

PROJECTS

retry — Go

A simple, stateless, functional mechanism to perform actions repetitively until successful.

Written as an exercise in creating a functional, clean, simple API design.

Used by Google (CadVisor), Canonical (Go-Dqlite), and WeWork (Grabbit)

define - Go

A command-line dictionary (thesaurus) app, with access to multiple sources, written in Go.

<u>One Mighty Roar</u> — Developer

JUN 2012 - DEC 2018

I worked with an eclectic, creative team, developing web and mobile applications and services for numerous clients.

A project I started there was spun-out into its own product and company, Robin. While at Robin, I still maintained some older OMR projects as needed.

<u>Plymouth State University</u> — Junior Developer

AUG 2008 - JUL 2012

I was a Junior developer and part of the MIS group at the university. I worked on smaller parts of large products in a team environment, and was responsible for the creation of the original Plymouth State University cross-platform (iOS/Android) mobile app.

EDUCATION

Plymouth State University, NH − B.S. in Computer Science

2008 - 2012

Developed and released the official PSU Mobile app (Android and iOS) for my senior project while being mentored by the MIS team.

incoming - PHP

Transform loose and complex input into consistent, strongly-typed data structures.

PHP NTLM - PHP

Message encoder/decoder and password hasher for NTLM.